Brecht Devleesschauwer PhD DVM MVSc MStat

Senior epidemiologist · Coordinator national burden of disease studies Sciensano, Department of Epidemiology and Public Health brecht.devleesschauwer@sciensano.be | brecht.cbra.be Rue Juliette Wytsman 14, 1050 Brussels, Belgium | +32 2 642 5035

Personal statement

The common goal of my research activities is to quantify the true impact of diseases and health inequalities, and to make model-based evaluations of prevention and control. I have developed and implemented the computational framework for estimating the global burden of foodborne disease, as an active member of the World Health Organization Foodborne Disease Burden Epidemiology Reference Group (WHO/FERG). Currently, I am implementing a Belgian national burden of disease study.

My research activities have led to more than 100 peer-reviewed scientific publications in national and international journals. My scientific expertise in burden assessment, risk assessment and health economics has been recognized through invitations to various national and international expert groups, including the Belgian Superior Health Council, the Belgian Food Safety Authority, and EFSA, WHO and FAO.

Education

2015	PhD Veterinary Sciences; Ghent University, Merelbeke, BE
	PhD Public Health; Université catholique de Louvain, Brussels, BE
2014	MSc Statistics; Katholieke Universiteit Leuven, Louvain, BE
2010	MSc Veterinary Medicine; Ghent University, Merelbeke, BE
2007	BSc Veterinary Medicine; Ghent University, Merelbeke, BE

Employment

2018-	Visiting professor, advanced epidemiology; UCL, Brussels, BE
2018-	Visiting professor, risk analysis; UGent, Merelbeke, BE
2016-	Senior epidemiologist; Sciensano, Brussels, BE
2016-18	Visiting professor, health economic evaluations; UCL, Brussels, BE
2015-16	Assistant scientist, global food safety and zoonoses; UF, Gainesville, USA
2015	Post-doctoral researcher; UGent, Merelbeke, BE
2013-14	Consultant; World Health Organization, Geneva, CH
2010-15	Doctoral researcher; UGent, Merelbeke, BE & UCL, Brussels, BE

Mentoring and supervision

2 PhD students \cdot 36 MSc students \cdot 8 BSc students

Scientific output

6 book chapters \cdot 121 peer-reviewed publications Google Scholar metrics: 3145 citations \cdot h-index 27 \cdot i10-index 54